MOHAMMED ARSHAD

Full Stack Developer

Portfolio | arshadchowdhury46@gmail.com | +8801317089432 GitHub | LinkedIn | Codewars | YouTube

About me

I've always loved technology, especially computers. From a young age, I was hooked on video games and fascinated by how they worked. Though I couldn't pursue a CS degree, my passion never faded. The 2020 COVID lockdown gave me a chance to reignite that passion. I used the time to teach myself software development through Google, YouTube and I've been loving every second of it since.

Skills

Languages: JavaScript | TypeScript | HTML | CSS | C & C++ (Basics)

Frameworks & Libraries: React | Next | Express | Nest | Angular | SCSS | TailwindCSS | Jest (Basics)

Databases: MongoDB | MySQL | PostgreSQL

Other Tech Skills - Git | GitHub | Debugging | Problem Solving | Slack | ClickUp | Teams etc. Soft Skills : Communication | Teamwork | Time Management | Patience | Creativity etc.

Work Experience

Software Developer (Full-Stack)

January 2024 - Present

Tutors Finland Oy | Espoo, Finland (Remote)

- Facing a new challenge here, my expertise was in React/Next but the codebase I'm working on currently is in Angular. I Took this challenge because I'm confident enough in JavaScript.
- The codebase was in Angular 10, we had to migrate it to Angular 16. I'm currently learning the nuances of Angular from scratch by fixing various issues in the codebase & building small personal projects parallelly because I think that's the best way to learn any new technology..
- Within 2 weeks in this role, I have managed to understand Angular to a level where I can fix the previous issues and implement some new features by myself without much supervision.
- Fixed some of the previous Stripe issues and documented them properly with a daily update log, bug tracking, bug fixes docs etc.

Software Developer (Frontend)

Replie I Dhaka, Bangladesh (Hyb

March 2023 - December 2023

Repliq | Dhaka, Bangladesh (Hybrid)

- Ensured robust and efficient data management by designing and integrating APIs for CRUD.
- Demonstrated expertise and learned handling Next.js 12/13, Axios, TanStack Query, Formik, yup, react-hot-toast, react slick, swiper.js, mobX and many other libraries without much supervision.
- Played a pivotal role in enhancing UI/UX significantly through numerous feature implementations.
- Collaborated effectively with the client, design and backend team, maintaining clear communication to convey project requirements within deadline.
- Accumulated 10 months of professional experience by contributing to three major projects.
- Actively participated in regular stand-up meetings (morning & evening) and other internal meetings, providing project updates and fostering a collaborative working environment.

Projects

Supplers -

A platform to let wholesalers & retailers connect in this global community for the furniture and interior design industry. A lot of functionalities are in here including authentication / authorization, connecting & being partners, admin dashboard, read - add - update - delete products/projects/services, file uploading/downloading, search, filter, sort, pagination, notifications, stripe and many more. Built it using Next.js 13 & Django. <u>Live site</u>

Chef Koochooloo -

I played a pivotal role in the development & enhancement of this educational platform. The project was in Angular 10, migrated it to Angular 16. Despite having no experience in Angular. I managed to learn Angular basics within 2 weeks & swiftly tackle 250-300 issues within the next 1 month, transforming a previously paused project into a smoothly running application within 1.5 months and built a lot of features in express as well. Live site —> Username - demostudent2 | Password - 123

My Dubai Properties -

This is a sophisticated real estate platform meticulously crafted for seamless property transactions in the vibrant city of Dubai. It is built with Next.js and used Axios, TanStack Query, React Hook Form, yup, react-hot-toast, react slick, swiper.js, Gsap and many more libraries, providing a robust foundation for a secure and efficient real estate marketplace with great UX for users. Wanted to share the live link of the app, but it seems the client is not maintaining the project anymore. Github Repo

Daraz Clone -

An e-commerce dummy platform. Used react hooks, react-slick-slider, font awesome, react router and some other packages in here which made the site look & feel good while using it. We can add to cart, remove from cart, update quantity of products in cart, react-hot-toast to give user feedback of activity and dynamic routing to each page of each product. Built it using React.js. <u>Live Site</u> <u>Github Repo</u>

E-bazaar App (Frontend) -

A dummy e-commerce app. We can add new products through a modal, then add products to cart and update the quantity of products in cart, delete from cart, generate a unique slug, provide a discount from start date to end date, a 25% discount to each product, search, pagination, loading state and side drawer for the cart. Built it using Next,js 13 App router with TypeScript. Live App Github Repo

I'm also an open source advocate. I have contributed to a couple of open source projects in Hacktoberfest. I got to learn a lot about forking, communicating, making PR's to Open source projects etc. Currently I'm learning DSA & Problem Solving to build up my core knowledge of programming.

Education

Southeast University Dhaka, Bangladesh

June 2015 - February 2020 LL.B.(Hons.)

Successfully completed my academic journey by earning an Honors Degree in Law in the year 2020.